Robertson Wang

Education

2008–2012 **BSc, Economics**, New York University.

Magna Cum Laude

2015–2016 **MSc, Economics**, *Universitat Pompeu Fabra*.

Fundación Ramón Arece Scholarship

2017 Data Science Certificate, Georgetown University.

Summary

My primary programming languages are Python and R. My main interests are in applications of machine learning and natural language processing. I am currently working on academic research using sentiment analysis and machine learning. I've also been involved in machine learning initiatives applying computation linguistics, neural networks, and NLP to image recognition and recommendation systems. I am well versed in sklearn, TensorFlow, SciPy, and nltk.

Day to day I use a variety of statistical modeling techniques and machine learning algorithms. These include ordinary least-squares regression, VAR, logistic regressions, neural networks, convolutional neural networks, support vector machines, and different vector models for characterizing text.

Experience

2016-current **Senior Research Assistant, Risk Analysis**, Federal Reserve Board, Washington DC.

Python & R Developer

- Co-Authored an academic paper using sentiment analysis to capture settings in which management communications have greater credibility
- Wrote web-scrappers in Python using BeautifulSoup, lxml, and selenium to acquire corpus of financial documents.
- Managed large unstructured datasets (10 tb+) on Hadoop, wrote BASH scripts and cron jobs to streamline the data pipeline.
- Developed multi-threaded code in Python to quickly process large amounts of natural language data, such as text from 10-K and earnings announcements
- Put into production NLP-based measures, built using Latent Dirichlet Allocation and word2vec, of emerging financial risk to help policy makers identify areas in need of stricter oversight
- Implemented parallelized data cleaning of large unstructured textual data using Apache Spark and a combination of R and Python deployed on a SLURM cluster
- Produced web-scrapping software in order to perform on-the-fly NLP analysis and classification of press releases with the goal of monitoring emerging areas of risk
- \circ Performed entity resolution and data cleaning on time series CDS data (10+gb/day) in order to produce quarterly risk profiles on FRB regulated banks
- Wrote multi-threaded Python code for cleaning large XML data and metadata files for news articles from Bloomberg, Dow Jones NewsWire, the New York Times, and Thomson Reuters

2018-current Data Science Consultant, Open Health Network, Washington DC.

Python & R Developer

- Created interactive web applications in R Shiny and Python Dash for researchers at Cornell University and the American Heart Association
- Managed streaming application and user data using AWS and mongoDB
- Wrote Python code to perform entity resolution across disparate mongoDB databases

135 Adams Street NW – Washington, DC 20001
☐ 1 (908) 745 8075 • ☑ robertsonwang@gmail.com
in www.linkedin.com/in/robertsonwang/ • ♠ robertsonwang.github.io

2012–2015 Financial Associate, Valuations & Modeling, Morgan Stanley, New York.

R Developer & Master of Excel Hell

- Created various regression models for asset pricing. Types of regression models that we used includes LASSO, Ridge, SVAR, and least-squares.
- o Created quantitative models to value securitized products (MBS, ABS, MBS Derivatives)
- Led methodology development on a option pricing model, based on Black-Scholes-Merton model, to price a bespoke REIT IPO.
- Designed databases, stored procedures, reports, and data input interfaces using SQL Server 2012, 2016 and PostgreSQL.
- o Automated reporting tasks using Python, VBA, and SQL.
- Wrote research reports on macroeconomic risk, local job market/housing market conditions, and real estate specific background.
- Worked with external auditors and firm counter parties to communicate and defend parameter estimations and model assumptions.
- o Managed and provided mentorship to a team of financial analysts and summer interns

Master thesis

Title Rational Bubbles And the Financial Accelerator

Supervisor Alberto Martin

A game theoretic approach to financial bubbles, wherein we model bubbles as a Pareto optimal outcome to a repeated coordination game.

Capstone Project

Title A NLP Restaurant Recommendation System Based On Yelp Reviews

We used a combination of unsupervised features trained on user reviews to recommend new restaurants to users. For each user, we test three different classification algorithms and select the best performing machine learning algorithm. We used XGBoost, Random Forest, and linear SVM.

Technical Skills

Statistical Matlab, R, Stata Packages

Programming Python, BASH, Java

Markup LaTeX, XML, MarkDown

Data Stores SQL, MongoDB, SAS

Big Data Apache Spark, Hadoop, SLURM

Office Excel, PowerPoint, Word

Relevant Coursework

- Machine Learning
- Probability Theory
- Time Series Analysis

- Data Visualization
- o Regression Models & Panel Data
- o State Space & Bayesian Models

Interests

Rock Climbing, Modern Literature, and Linguistics